产品经理国际资格认证(NPDP)

PDMA是全球产品开发和管理领域最大的协会。其使命为提升组织和个人在产品开发和管理领域的能力。创建于1979年，PDMA为会员提供产品领域的专业级开发资源、信息和合作，以推动新产品开发和管理。
新产品开发和服务涉及到一系列特定的活动。PDMA是唯一专注于产品经理职业发展的组织，并能够在提供教育、经验、网络和认证等领域提供助力

http://www.pdma.org/
www.chinanpdp.com    PDMA国家外专局NPDP考试注册中心
http://www.tcsafea.org.cn/pdma/index.html  PDMA国家外专局NPDP考试注册中心
http://www.npdp.net/portal.php?mod=list&catid=1

NPDP：产品经理国际资格认证（New Product Development Professional）
PDMA：美国产品开发与管理协会（Product Development & Management Association）

NPDP是国际公认的唯一的新产品开发专业认证，集理论方法与实践为一体的全方位知识体系，为公司组织层级进行规划、决策、执行提供良好的方法体系支持 。它由PDMA颁发，该协会成立于1979年，是全球范围内产品开发与管理专业人士最杰出的倡导者，协助个人、企业或组织提升其产品开发与管理的能力与成效。PDMA推出的“新产品开发管理知识体系”受到全球500大企业采用，并证实能有效提升新产品开发的成功几率，是产品经理解决工作难题最有效的专业方法论。2016年4月NPDP产品经理国际认证正式引进中国。

NPDP Mainland China Program
PDMA is excited to announce a new partnership with the Training Center of the State Administration of Foreign Experts Affairs, P.R.C. (TCSAFEA) to bring the NPDP Certification Program to China on a more local level. This partnership allows students in mainland China to apply for and take the NPDP exam through TCSAFEA, instead of submitting an application to PDMA and taking the exam through Prometric.
If you are located in mainland China and would like to begin the NPDP application and exam process, please click on the button below.
For questions on your application, related fees, or the NPDP exam schedule, please contact TCSAFEA directly at:
TCSAFEA
www.chinanpdp.com 
npdp@safea.gov.cn
86-10-68948899-50420 86-10-68948805


To live is to change the world-Jobs


产品经理认证（NPDP）知识体系指南
产品开发与管理协会 著

https://item.jd.com/12186278.html#none


国家外国专家局培训中心与美国产品开发与管理协会（PDMA）于2016年4月16日签署合作协议，将PDMA制定的全球唯一的产品经理国际资格认证（NPDP）体系引入中国。
